# **Richard Tuttle**

(208) 850 – 9424 | richardtuttle@me.com | Riverside, CA LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/richard-tuttle | Portfolio: rtuttlecoder.github.io

# **Lead Senior Developer**

A lead senior-level Developer and technologically creative person possessing the ability to diagnose and solve problems in a technology-driven environment who also loves developing impactful web experiences; a team player who can deliver world-class, user-centered products and services; and, managerial and mentoring experience.

### **SKILLS**

- Program Management
- Full Life Cycle Design
- Product Development
- Agile/Scrum
- Remote Working/Tools
- Problem Solving
- Mentoring & Managerial
- Team Player

- API/REST Integration(s)
- ADA/ARIA Compliancy
- Instructional Design
- WordPress expert
- Responsive Design
- Mobile-first Design

### Platforms, CMSes, and Frameworks

Vue/Nuxt, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Jekyll, WordPress, React, Express.js, ZenCart, openCart, Joomla, Magento, MongoDB, BuilderIO, Prismic, Contentful, Pantheon

#### **Tools**

Git, Pug, EJS, Flexbox, Authorize.net, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Illustrator, MS Office Suite, Google Analytics, WHM, cPanel, Docker, Sketch, AWS, TeamViewer, LogMeIn, ScreenConnect, Webpack, Babel, Node, Zoom. Figma

### Languages

HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Typescript, PHP, MySQL, XML, Python, Liquid, Java, JSON

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

22squared, Atlanta, GA Lead Senior Developer (Remote) 2020 - present

- Conceptualize and develop client projects throughout the creation cycle
- Work with a wide-array of technologies in evaluating and scoping projects
- Utilize modern frameworks and technology to give a great end-user experience
- Mentor junior-level Developers on their projects and skills
- Work with Project Managers and QA analysts to bring projects to complete fruition
- API integrations from variety of vendors
- Utilize agile development techniques to work through project timelines
- Troubleshoot, debugged, and solved cross-browser issues
- Leveraged tools for assessing ADA and usability compliance
- Project research and findings with Executives
- CMS integrations expert
- Train staff and client, as needed, on the various technology creations

NIC, Inc. / Access Idaho, Boise, ID Lead Front-end & WordPress Developer (partial Remote) 2017 - 2020

- Assisted in the maintenance and enhancements of Idaho.gov
- Customized Idaho's WordPress library of services
- Built websites for customers based on Idaho templates
- Maintained and updated Idaho State templates and documentation according to Idaho standards and latest information

### Richard Tuttle | richardtuttle@me.com | rtuttlecoder.github.io | Page Two

- Met with stakeholders to conceptualize and develop interactive content, generated concepts/mockups, gathered information and created websites based on customer needs
- Trained/assisted customers in maintaining their own WordPress websites
- Provided continued support for sites already launched via troubleshooting, bug fixes, instructional help, etc.
- Assisted in user-interface design and testing of online applications and websites
- Troubleshoot, debugged, and solved cross-browser issues
- Leveraged tools for assessing ADA and usability compliance
- · Assisted with user research and usability testing efforts
- Developed & built static sites utilizing templating frameworks
- Contributed creatively to the growth of the company

### Northwind, Inc., Boise, ID Sr. Web Developer (partial Remote)

2011 - 2017

- Built websites for B2C, B2B, and Nonprofit customers utilizing various platforms: WordPress, Joomla, Drupal, ZenCart, openCart, Magento, as well as custom developed/programmed sites
- Provided continued support for customers via troubleshooting, bug fixes, instructional help, etc.
- Aided in the corporation's increase in profit margin by 58%

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Technical proofer for Computer Networking Technology, 2nd Ed. Delmar Publishing
- Proofer for PHP for the World Wide Web: Visual QuickStart Guide, 2nd Ed. Peachpit Press "Working the Web: a four-part series" for The Newsletter
- Technical proofer for Computer Networking Technology Delmar Publishing
- "Where Web Design Begins" for HomeBizAdvice "Website Maintenance Tutorial" for HTMLCenter
- Principle author of Pure HTML: a reference Macmillan Computer Publishing (Sams.Net)

(More titles available upon request)

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- World Organization of Webmasters
- International Webmasters Association
- Association of Internet Professionals
- PDX PHP Group (co-founder)
- HTML Writers Guild
- Linguistics Society of America
- American Orientalist Society
- American Classical Association
- Inducted into the "Phi Alpha Theta" honor society

## **EDUCATION and CERTIFICATIONS**

- ⇒ Bachelor Degree University of Maryland
- ⇒ Associate Degree Portland Community College
- ⇒ Certified "Google Analytics Advisor" by Google
- ⇒ Certified "Authorize.net Developer" by Authorize.net
- ⇒ Idaho Limited Occupational Specialist certification, endorsed for Information/Communication Technology
- ⇒ Technical Conference Workshops/Tutorials: ConnectTech, SmashingConf, OSCON, Fluent, WebConf, NuxtCon, VueCon, etc.